阿尔卡拉斯 6-3 4-6 13-11 弗里茨 · 赛后场上采访
We have Roger Federer in the front row,
前排坐着罗杰·费德勒，
Sir Andy Murray in the front row.
前排还有安迪·穆雷爵士
I'm not even sure they would play
我都不确定他们在那种时候
the drop shot at times
敢不敢放小球
when you play the drop shot.
而你放了
You're down match point,
你被对手拿到赛点
you have a match point.
你自己也拿到赛点
How do you have the confidence
你哪来的自信
to hit drop shots in those huge moments?
在那么关键的时刻放小球？
Well, I mean, I just, I feel,
嗯 我是说 我觉得
I feel the drop shot is, you know,
我觉得放小球
part of my, of my game already.
已经是我打法的一部分
And, you know, I just, I'm trying to use it,
我就是想用它
you know, in my favor, you know, I think,
让它为我所用 我觉得
you know, the drop shot that I made,
我在这场比赛里放的小球
you know, in the match, I think I won.
我觉得都赢下来了
If not, you know, every drop shot, at least,
就算不是每一个 至少
you know, a really high percentage of it.
成功率也非常高
So, you know, in those moments,
所以在那些时刻
in those really close
在那些比分很接近
and important moments,
又很关键的时刻
I tried to use it because it was a, it
我就试着用它 因为它
was a really good weapon for me, you know,
对我来说是非常好的武器
in this match.
在这场比赛里
And obviously I have been practicing
而且我从很小的时候
the drop shot since I was a little kid.
就一直在练放小球
So it's part of, it's part of my game already.
所以这已经是我打法的一部分
Not all stadiums
不是每座球场
have a jumbotron like we have at the O2.
都有O2这样的大屏幕
You hit some incredible shots,
你打出了一些不可思议的球
you always do.
你一向如此
Tonight, I saw you looking up at some
今晚我看到你抬头看
of your own replays.
自己的回放
Do you ever look at your own replays
你会不会看着自己的回放
and say, you know what, that's not bad.
说 你知道吗 还不赖
Sometimes, you know,
有时候吧
I just, I mean, I, I love, I love tennis
我是说 我真的很爱网球
and that when, when sometimes, you know,
有时候
not even in my match or not even my shots,
甚至不是我的比赛 不是我的球
the opponent's shots,
是对手的球
when it's a really, a really great shot
当那是一记特别精彩的球
or great points, I really like to, you know,
或者一分 我真的很喜欢
rewatch it.
再看一遍
Why not?
为什么不呢？
I think one of the, you know,
我觉得有一件
one of the things that I'm going to tell,
我要去说一件事
you know, every tournament
跟每站比赛都说
is to take off all the, you know, screens
就是把所有屏幕都撤掉
that I'm not trying not to, you know,
免得我
lose the focus on the matches, you know,
在比赛里分心
rewatching the points, but you know,
去看回放 不过
anyways, it's a, for me, it's great.
总之 对我来说这很棒
And it is a moment that I can, you know,
这是一个能让我
relax myself and still go, keep going.
放松一下 然后继续往前的时刻
Team World won both matches
世界队今天下午
this afternoon.
两场都赢了
You guys
你们
were only down two points heading
只落后两分
into this match,
进入这场比赛
but did you feel like it was a must-win match
但你是不是觉得这场必须赢
for yourself and team Europe?
对你自己和欧洲队来说？
Yes, I mean, two great
是的 今天输了两场
and tough losses today.
都很艰难
And obviously I was thinking a little bit
而且我当然想到了
about last year that we lost, you know,
去年周六
every match, you know, on Saturday.
我们每一场都输了
So I didn't, I, you know, coming to the match,
所以来比赛的时候
I was trying not to let it happen again.
就想别让它再发生
So I was kind of nervous at the beginning.
所以一开始我有点紧张
I'm not going to lie, but really, really happy
不骗你们 但真的非常高兴
that I took the win at the end.
最后我拿下了
And, you know, I'm probably,
而且我可能
or I hope that I just made, you know,
或者说我希望 我刚才
my players and the doubles next to me,
让队友们和打双打的两位
you know, a little bit relaxed
稍微放松一点
and not feeling the pressure at all.
完全不用感到压力
And finally, you do this better
最后 这一点你
than almost any athlete I've ever seen.
比我见过的几乎所有人都强
In moments of stress,
在有压力的时候
in times where you're losing,
在落后的时候
you have a smile on your face.
你脸上还带着笑
How do you keep a smile on your face
你是怎么做到
during those tough times?
在那些艰难时刻还笑得出来？
What the hell?
搞什么？
I'm too young still, though, so.
不过我还太年轻了
Well, what was the question? I'm sorry.
嗯 问题是什么来着？抱歉
It was during times of stress,
是说在有压力的时候
how do you keep a smile on your face
你怎么做到一直笑着
at all times?
在任何时候？
Well, it's, I try, you know,
嗯 我努力
because every time that I smile,
因为每次我笑的时候
it feels like I'm having fun and I'm relaxed,
就觉得自己玩得开心 很放松
my body.
身体也是
And, you know, when that time comes,
而当那种时候到来
you know, it's when I play my best tennis,
就是我打出最好网球的时候
when I'm relaxed, when I'm happy,
当我放松 当我开心
when I'm enjoying the moment.
当我享受当下的时候
You know, I think one
我觉得
of the most important things to accept,
最重要的事情之一是接受
accept the moment,
接受当下
even if it is break one down, break one up,
不管落后还是领先一个破发
you know, really six hours in time,
真的是六个小时
where you have to accept that moment
你都得接受那一刻
and go for it all the time.
并且一直全力以赴
So when I'm just thinking about this, there
所以当我想到这件事
is a tennis match, there is a, it is a game
这是一场网球比赛 是一场游戏
and I realize that it is when I'm keep enjoying
我意识到 就是当我一直享受
and pull off my great tennis
才打得出我最好的网球
and my great sauce.
还有我的绝活
So that's why I just, I'm trying to have fun
所以我才会尽量
as much as I can.
让自己玩得开心
Well done today, congratulations.
今天打得漂亮 恭喜
You've tied things up.
你把比分扳平了
Carlos Alcaraz.
卡洛斯·阿尔卡拉斯